THOMAS ORTHBANDT

Website Manager & Frontend Developer

CONTACT

PHONE:

(650) 248-4620

WEBSITE:

thomas-orthbandt.com

EMAIL:

torthbandt@gmail.com

SKILLS

Languages: HTML, SASS, JS, React, PHP, VML

Repo: Github, Codepen, JSFiddle

CMS: Wordpress, Adobe AEM, SDL Tridion

Email: Marketo, Hubspot, Pardot

Testing: Optimize, Optimizely, UAT, PageSpeed Insights, Litmus, Email-on-Acid, Vector

Markup (VML)

Graphics: Photoshop, Figma, SVG **Search**: SEO, Yoast, SEMRush

Analytics: Google Analytics, Tag Manager **Project Mgmt:** Agile Proj. Mgmt (APM)

ADA: AXE DevTools

EDUCATION

San Diego State University 1995 – 1997

Bachelor: International Business

- **Minor**: Western European Business/German
- Phi Kappa Psi fraternity Founding Father

College of San Mateo 1991–1995

Associates: Business Administration

HUMBOLDT UNIVERSITAT

Berlin, Germany

International Studies: Int'l Business & German

SUMMARY

I am an experienced **Website Project Manager** and **Frontend Developer** with over 20 years of experience developing and managing websites. Proficient in HTML, CSS, JS (ES5/6), and other relevant programming languages.

I am keen on driving data driving analytics, web optimization strategies, SEO, and executing digital marketing to drive website enablement and conversions.

WORK EXPERIENCES

WEST COAST UNIVERSITY, Irvine, CA (Remote – Contract) Sept. 2022 – Present *Sr. Website Project Manager*

Responsibilities:

- Lead the web strategy: For WCU.com & ACC.com, CRO, Analytics, UX, and UAT
- Front-end: HTML, CSS, Vanilla JavaScript, PHP, VML
- Emails: Develop email templates from scratch & tested using Email on Acid
- Performance improvement: A/B testing aligned to short-term and long-term goals
- Analyze and monitor: Page performance, UX, implement data driven hypotheses
- SEO: Initiate content opportunities that improve website visibility & performance.
- Collaborate: Marketing, Engineering, Creative, and Product teams to create site

Achievements: Project managed WCU.com site migration from homegrown CMS to Wordpress in March 2023. Optimized Google Tag Manager tags, triggers, and variables for cleaner Google Analytic reporting on Events, Page Views, and Conversions, increase Page Views and Conversions by 33%. Increase Organic SEO traffic by 28.32% over past 6 months, Non-branded clicks went up 81.08% YoY. Lead generation efforts increased application completion and enrollment MoM.

CLOROX, Oakland, CA (Remote – Contract)

July 2021 - Sept. 2022

Sr. Frontend and Email Developer

Responsibilities:

1992

- Front-end: Developer for Clorox websites brands Clorox.com, kingsford.com, hiddenvalley.com, glad.com, and brita.com
- Emails: Develop email templates for all Clorox brands from scratch & tested using Litmus
- Repository: GitHub and git CLI to maintain content control and Peer Review
- **Project Manage**: **JIRA** to manage tasks and to assign and prioritize projects
- CMS: WordPress content management using Timber, Vanilla JS, and SCSS
- Testing: Optimizely, HotJar, UAT, QA, Web optimization, and ADA compliance
- Collaborate: Partner with Marketing, Content, Design, QA, and Engineering

Technologies: HTML5, SCSS, Vanilla JS, PHP, Timber, GitHub/Docker, VML

Achievements: Developed and created Hidden Valley Lucky Draw interactive card game to win recipes and grand prizes. Developed many landing pages for Clorox, Glad, Kingsford, and Brita. Developed email templates for Hidden Valley, Glad, Kingsford, Fresh Steps, and Clorox Pro email templates and verified all templates worked with MS Outlook using VML. All testing done through Litmus before emails would go live.

HIREVUE, Salt Lake City, UT (Remote – FTE)

Corporate Website Marketing Manager

Feb 2020 - July 2021

Responsibilities:

- Manage: hirevue.com, SEO, SEM, Lead Forms, Analytics, Sales Cycle
- Development: Hirevue Wordpress Theme, Frontend with ReactJs (Headless WP)
- Emails: Develop all templated emails from scratch & tested using Email on Acid

- Analytics: Page Views, Enablement, Conversions, and Goal Completions
- Web Mechanics: Manage website infrastructure, Security, & troubleshooting
- Conversion Testing: Optimizely, HotJar Heatmap, AXE ADA Compliance
- **Personalization**: ABM 6Sense, Optimizely, and Marketo Personalization
- Collaborate: Partner with Marketing, Sales, Product, and Engineering
- Project Manage: Run weekly Asana tasks to review, assign, and prioritize projects; review efficiency & quality, and hit target dates
- Communication: Slack and Asana to communicate and manage projects
- Technologies: HTML, SCSS, JS/jQuery, React, PHP, Timber

Achievements: Ran the entire hirevue.com site from development, maintenance, blog support, analytics, SEO, lead form implementation (Marketo) and ABM personalization (6sense). Big achievement creating a Covid Microsite within 2 weeks after world shutdown continuing our support of businesses and clients during this troubling time. From 2020 to 2021, the website helped drive \$21 million in new revenue with solid lead generation and increase Search and SEO efforts.

NOMINUM/AKAMAI, Redwood City, CA (FTE) Corporate Website Project Manager

May 2016 - Feb 2020

Responsibilities:

- Project Manage: Nominum.com website/lead generation development, SEO, ABM, A/B Testing, Web analytics, Internet trends/Best Practices, and Website optimization
- Emails: Develop all Nominum & Akamia email templates from scratch
- Testing: Optimizely, HotJar, Litmus
- CMS: Nominum WordPress Theme creation, plugin & custom development
- Web Security: Akamai Kona Site Defender, IPv6 and SSL certification
- SEO: Keyword optimization and best practices using Yoast
- Analytics: Google Analytics and Google Tag Manager for pixel tracking integration
- Personalization: Increased website traffic and forms with DemandBase
- Lead Generation: Pardot and Marketo Emails and form development
- Collaborate: Partner with Marketing, Sales, Product and Technical teams
- Technologies: PHP, SCSS, JS/jQuery, HTML5, Photoshop/Sketch

Achievements: Redesigned Nominum.com, updated navigation and restructured SEO which doubled organic Search within first 3 months of being hired. Migrated hosting to Pantheon and decreased annual costs by over \$20k with this migration. Helped the Demand Gen team also migrate to Pardot and implemented all form leads on Nomimun.com for better conversions and thought leadership SEO through brand awareness. After Akamai acquisition of Nominum, moved to Automation team and helped increase Akamai's lead conversions over 9 different countries, including creating dynamic Landing Pages and Emails for each region.

XERO, San Francisco, CA (FTE)

Aug 2014 - May 2016

Sr. Frontend Developer

Responsibilities:

- **Develop**: All Web pages for xero.com
- Emails: Develop all Xero email templates from scratch in Marketo
- Mobile App: Helped launch iOS mobile app Xero Touch app
- CMS: Umbraco and migrated to Adobe AEM
- Repository: GitHub and git to maintain content control and Peer Review
- Lead Generation: Pardot and Marketo Emails and form development
- Partnerships: Partnered with Design & Copywriters to deliver polished Webpages
- Technologies: HTML5, CSS/SCSS, JS/jQuery, SVG, Grunt/git, Photoshop

Achievements: Ran all marketing landing pages and email development for Xero US marketing. Helped build the Xero Touch iOS App and was on the team to migrate the CMS from Umbraco to Adobe AEM. Ran lead gen through Pardot and then

helped migrate to Marketo where I created email templates from scratch and used Marketo snippets for re-use components.

the state of the s

INTUIT, Mountain View, CA (Contract)

Dec 2012 - Aug 2014

Sr. Web Developer

Responsibilities:

- **Develop**: All QBO lead generation, A/B testing (**SiteSpect**)
- Emails: Develop QBO email templates and Tested using Litmus
- CMS: Adobe AEM
- Development: Led front-end web development, prototyping, regular maintenance (QBO), ATG platform, and Perforce Version Control
- Technologies: HTML5, CSS3 (SASS), JS (jQuery), Photoshop

ATMEL, San Jose, CA (Contract)

Dec 2009 - Dec 2012

Sr. Web Developer

Responsibilities:

- Manage: website redesign and re-architect web structure
- **Development**: Developed modularizing structure, component, schema-based
- Emails: Directed email development and deployment
- CMS: Implemented SDL Tridion (migrated 25k pages)
- Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, JS/jQuery, XML, Photoshop

VMWARE, Palo Alto, CA (Contract)

Apr 2009 - Dec 2009

Sr. Web Producer

Responsibilities:

- **Development:** new web pages using W3C standards & accessibility
- Manage: Ensured cross-browser compatibility
- Partner: with designers and other web developers
- Analytics: Ran analytics using Omniture reporting system

INTUIT, Mountain View, CA (FTE)

Apr 2009 – Dec 2009

Sr. Web Producer

Responsibilities:

- Development: Developed marketing emails, landing pages, microsites, and intranets
- Manage: Project managed all web marketing campaigns for QuickBooks and Quicken
- Analytics: Ran web analytic reports (HBX & Omniture)
- CMS: Managed web content using TeamSite
- Collaborate: Developed strong working relationships with cross-functional teams
- Technologies: XHTML, JavaScript (JS), CSS, XML, Flash, Photoshop

ORACLE, Redwood City, CA (FTE)

Feb 1999 – Apr 2009

Marketing Manager/Web Producer

Responsibilities:

- Development: Led development initiatives for Oracle Partner Network (OPN) redesign
- CMS: Migrated from Oracle Content Management System (CMS) to Oracle9iAS
 Portal
- Partnerships: Partnered with Portal dev team to increase functionality and security
- Project Manage: Project managed life cycle using Oracle Collaboration Suite
- Technologies: XHTML, JavaScript (JS), CSS, Flash

References upon Request